hello and welcome to the
game b together tech round table
um on saturdays different times
depending on
uh where you are in the world and uh
we're doing mornings and evenings this
is our first kind of
later in the day one
so the the plan uh for this as usual is
we
go around talk about uh give a little
spiel about our project short and sweet
and then we um talk about things that
we've accomplished things that we hope
to accomplish and if we need any help
and then usually we try and find one or
two people that are willing to be
on the what's called the hot seat it's
just a place where they talk
more in depth about challenges they're
having and how we can all
help them out and outside that we can
work on our
uh on any combined projects we're
working on
so who would like to start us off with
an update
i could start uh solution raising this
week we held
two one was our usual one on wednesday
that we did on loneliness which was very
impactful i enjoyed that one
and then the next day bentley and carrie
joined and we had one on voting with
your wallet with mark campbell and
they both i think went really well as
well as meeting with carrie and yvette
before this conversation a few hours ago
and coming up with um things are going
to facilitate our
three projects and something else that
uh carrie remember what is the
we no starting with three we something
starting with three and i can't remember
what is it
the culture of three starts
yeah the culture three
because all three of us are
concentrating on that the culture of we
like the difference between eye culture
and we culture and what happens we come
together
so it's where our projects overlap and
so the culture of we and then we were
talking about three so what came up was
yes we're starting just
conversations and seeing what comes out
of that so that is my week i don't have
anything
to sit the hot seat for i think that is
what is going to happen with the uh
culture of we and so i will pass it on
to whatever else just next
all right i guess i can go next uh so my
project is
wikilection uh it is a project to fight
misinformation
in politics religion and science and
religion sorry politics news and science
um i've been working with
another person that shows up to these
sessions matush and bentley has been
helping as well
to get the first version of the
prototype online i've got sort of the
early days version online and now we're
working at adding the part to track
uh legislation and voting and then we'll
continue to expand it
there's also been sort of a side project
that
may or may not involve a bunch of other
people which is the other side of that
uh currently being i'm calling it
conferrati and that is more for the
organization side
um and that hasn't technically started
but kind of has because it's just going
to end up being
the other side of the same uh sort of
piece of software that is
running the wiki election prototype um
but i've been working with matush on
that there hasn't been
too much progress in the last i think
two weeks because we've been getting
caught up on upwork
um my next step is to work on some of
the sample data for the legislation
so nothing terribly exciting
okay we started with um i've realized
we've got three projects well
four now on the go but um they all kind
of
play into the the bigger picture so um
hope to build a
a website and um as a bit of an idiot
because i've got to chase the david
saver so that's
put me back a day or so um third place
stuff i need to build business plans for
that which i'm still in the process of
gathering information
and i realized because i like doing
crochet and stuff um but
i realized last week that i could
probably start um bad nana beans as a
collective for
crocheting crafts and stuff like that
and see where that goes
and then as jubilee said the the culture
of we started with three so i had a good
really chat
real good chat with them yvette and
jubilee today and that feeds into the
bigger picture
and hope it'll lead to a lot of
solidarity
and a lot of helping each other out and
building success into sort of like all
the projects and
not just for us but for everybody else
as well so i think
oh and i might be getting into a
story about uh oral history project
story project that's
probably in the often and plus the fact
that an audio play what i had an idea
for
and managed to find a producer to turn
it into
so like a a podcast series so i'm really
excited about that and
other stuff that's coming up that i did
ages ago that i thought was dead
is getting resurrected which is even
better so um yeah fingers in lots of
pies
all right um so
i was working on reason score but
um starting to realize even though i
kind of built the project
um i don't know that i have the stamina
to put in a lot of the data
and i think um people
i think if there's not some certain
amount of data in there already i'm not
sure people would participate i'm not
even sure that people would be at
most people would be adding in data just
because it's such a
it's more i think people want it to
mostly be
done by experts and then they would come
in and add their two cents
so i'm think considering hiring someone
to do
some kind of internet research and maybe
hold my hand while we
enter some data into the system and see
how it works
i still think the process is good but
it just made it's so thought intensive
uh once you i think reading it's easy
but writing is hard
um it's kind of like writing a a book
you know it takes a
it can take some people up to a year to
write a book but it only takes you
10 hours to read or whatever um
and then i was also kind of inspired by
our talks about
um uh systems where people can
rate and review and kind of choose
things based on that so it
encompasses food and politics and
software
so i've been thinking about a kind of a
core open source software that would
facilitate all those use cases
that would be kind of a no code easy
startup
easy thing to start maybe and
also building tools that are
kind of like no code but jubilee has
kind of talked to the past on how
you know it's great that there's all
this open source software but unless you
have a programmer you obviously
often can't start it and there's a
couple tools nowadays where you can't
actually click a button it'll
load it up to a host of your choice
and then you just have to pay that host
for hosting costs and then you can adapt
it
but a lot of those are very house
specific so i'm trying to make a generic
one that'll work in
you know where you can do it with a
small hosting company or
with amazon or microsoft or whoever you
want
so i've been writing up documentation on
what i think to do that
and then maybe we'll have meeting next
friday to go through the
with voting with your wallet sort of
thing
which is just one aspect i need to be
careful i don't
try and change what anyone's trying to
do by trying to generalize it too much
uh yeah so i've been kind of thinking
through that process and i've been kind
of
i'm trying to think i might want to get
a part-time job because
um i'm kind of losing steam on all my
projects and i think it'd be nice to
have someone hand me some work i could
do for a little while rather than
having to every day figure out what i
need to do
and make a little cash and extend this
experiment but i don't know that's what
i've been thinking
so i guess it didn't really say what
reason score does and i don't know if we
all kind of did that
but um that's a it's a mass agreement
tool so it helps
people find agreement on contentious
issues through
evidence and reason
um so yeah that's it for me i was
thinking maybe when we do this in the
future maybe we could just
decide to go clockwise from the top um
because i think we're all in the same
position we have jubilee at the top
adriel and then kerry and then me does
everyone else
see that same clockwise from the top
left
yeah you're under me right bentley yeah
yeah the other problem is i think
if i if i point this way i'm pointing at
carrie aren't i
no you've got a point this way oh okay
yeah yeah
right because of the because of the
camera i tried to mirror it but i forgot
oh yeah you're right okay so she's over
there
it's always fun to play with the mirrors
on this one that was one of the things
that ended up with that
point adrian but not for anyone else but
this one it's good
yeah okay it is it is um not mirrored
for me and some of the tools
the mirror yours so it looks less weird
but then the whole
angles get off um
yeah yeah so um i don't know if i
have anything for the hot seat i mean
i'd like to talk about that
that that uh surveying tool the
but i don't want to
design it too much without the other
participants
but yeah and when you say surveying
tools that the vote was your wallet
thing yeah
oh it just muted you yeah community
review okay
community rating ratings probably a
better word
okay yeah i'm okay with uh
and i think we can sort of talk about
that because
we have a level of talking about that
that affects all of our projects
and then there will be a level on on
friday
where it's about a specific project and
we can sort of talk about what that's
trying to achieve
yeah but i mean i think yeah there's so
many projects about
sort of community review and that's
definitely core part of
wikilection and so it might be sort of
like if you're interested in
building sort of like a tool that could
work for multiple things
in theory we could just say hey what
would you know
reason score and wikilection need to be
able to use this so we have a starting
point
and when we talk about this other
project how does that fit into
so carrie did did you have anything that
you especially want to be on the hot
seat about i know jubilee said she
didn't
um i'm kind of specific it's more about
asking yourselves
is that the whole right in terms of
well well yeah this stuff but i'm going
to do a jubilee first
and then i'll come come for the boy
scouts
cause you'll be the boy scouts um
well i'd like to know right right in an
ideal world
and your projects are up and running
right do you have a number of people
in your head that you might be wanting
to
to be using this as a i don't know like
bentley would you be
creating a community around your reason
school
and also adriel would you be creating a
community around you your wicked
election and if so
how many people would you would you like
to see
in each whether it be a community that
gets um
they gravitate around that and obviously
you've got the big wide world which is
full of people
but there'll be a maybe a community that
could have gravitate
around your project right during
worcester as i said i'm just looking
because i know jubilee's after ten
thousands right so
that's that bit um but you too i'm not
too sure how many people
um you'd want to so like gravitate
toward
what would be an ideal community size in
terms of people
would you would you have around your
project
yeah i think for mine it would end up
being
different levels of involvement kind of
like probably
wikipedia where you know there's sort of
some people that actually like go you
know and spend a lot of time on it and
geek out i may occasionally change a few
things
um and then there's the people who like
you know there's that guy who's i think
published like 10 thousand or a hundred
thousand
articles or some insane number like that
and then there's you know just the the
regular user that might just find a
wikipedia page when they google
something
and they go there and look at it and
then they did
they they move on so i think um
oh hey matu is here even though it's
quite late for him um
so i think on the community side the
like end users
you know the end goal is for that to be
like in the billions because it's you
know
right it's like a a global political
thing
that's you know way down the road i
think real
realistically if it were to get let's
say 10 000 like
core users that would be awesome that
would
you know probably actually be close to
the numbers that
if it were really successful that would
probably be around the core number of
users like somewhere
between 5 000 and 50 000 and then you
might get into like the tens and huh
hundreds of thousands for like the the
dabblers people you know who would
go in there and check things out i may
occasionally like throw a rock at
something and be like hey is that right
or you know some form of a comment but
right
so in terms of contributors right how
many people how many people would you
like in terms of contribute
contributors
i mean that's where it gets weird
because just on the political side
you know probably in the thousands where
it would probably end up being like
you know maybe a hundred or a couple
hundred in canada and then you know
easily into the thousands in the us and
it would probably be split to different
countries right when it comes to like
the
discussing evidence side definitely in
the thousands
right okay nice or you know or to the
many many thousands because if we're
talking about like
people just discussing science and
people discussing you know the various
economics um the goal is for it to be a
fairly large number of people who are
qualified
in that area and then you know if each
of them
reviews anywhere from 10 to 100
studies you could end up getting a
pretty good breath of knowledge being
reviewed okay right okay
how about you bentley
so um reason score is kind of a generic
tool so there might be several
communities using it for different
purposes but if we
kind of narrow it down to maybe like the
goalie bot use of it
gilibot being a public character
that helps people make decisions on a
on a society-wide basis um
like you know is global warming
something we need to work on or should
we send our kids back to school
this season while we're in the middle of
a pandemic or at the end of a pandemic
so for that i mean i would imagine it
would be fairly successful
if we had a thousand
contributors right and then you know
tens of thousands of
readers okay um
so yeah that would be that would be a
fairly good start
okay specific piece yeah right it's okay
because i was just
trying to get a feel for kind of numbers
you know what i mean um see how you know
you would need to collect for you
collect and keep as awesome as you are
carrie you're
definitely not on the hook for getting
ten thousand people
that's that's a lot we're only expecting
a thousand from you
matus do you want to give your update
and uh let us know what you're up to
uh not much i had a
very chaotic week so
uh i ate some stuff but it wasn't
much so
yeah that's pretty much about it and
it it's the same for uh didn't do much
for week election as well
uh i intends to catch up this this
weekend i mean when i finish
what i am doing right now uh tonight
tomorrow night
uh to close this week on positive note
and
uh implement what got into the
this document for uh improvements
so that would be my goal and for
hyperlogos
i need to write a description a
manifesto i can it's not
it's only adjacent to game b so i can
write a manifesto
and uh yes
and something like a description so uh
it can be presented on the like first
as kind of a landing page for the for
the project
because right now it has no landing page
at all it displays
weird stuff when you enter it so
that's it
all right thanks i think bentley we were
gonna have you in the hot seat we can
art
unless matu said something i think did
we answer your question fully carry or
did you have more
that was oh yeah it's just um a two
straight
so see when you get hyper lugos on the
go
how many people would you like to be
involved in
terms of contributing to the code base
or to the well just to to the project um
maybe i don't know using it or
helping other people using it or if you
if do
you envisage your community being built
up around
the hyperlogos because that's the kind
of thing i'm looking at
i would expect the hyperlogos itself
as a generic software to have just a few
because that's the way with
open source projects so i definitely do
not expect much
money on the other hand
on specific instances of it um
when there is um a
subject or a purpose to this to the
given instance
uh i would expect a tens
to hundreds right okay but if i if i
have even a ten
uh that would be uh i consider it a
success
marches do you see there being kind of a
public
group one that's kind of open or do you
think it'll always be a specific
instance
uh i have an idea uh
idea on this that kerry would would
that's the community i think kerry would
be
focusing on yes there will be something
like
uh like this uh ideally because
uh for
in the initial stage there would be
instances
only uh each instance with specific
purpose
and um theme and so on
but a public instance to you know
gather them all in one big tree of
information
uh that's something i would like to have
in uh
unspecified future so yes
it would be like a tree of trees and
something containing
descriptions and links to all instances
that are public and within the same
scope like if the scope is improving the
world
and there are 10 or whatever
however many specific instances for uh
specific purposes
um this one public instance would be the
like main landing page
and um source of initial information
uh sending users to specific um
branches so to speak do you also make
sure what you'd what would either
forest get in a forest
first round forest
yeah do do you envision one of these for
like the game b
community or is it more specific than
that okay
so if we had the game b community that
would be
a couple hundred people by maybe
participating
uh looking at it uh actively adding
information to it
um if i have 10 people actively adding
information
given how uh in our environment
in the context of everything being
voluntary
then it's um not as easy
yeah unless uh there is some incentive
involved
um not in for form of money but
uh like rewards points
like you know in warcraft you have
pieces of gold
so it could be something like this
slight gamification of those
of this project who knows i don't like
the word and i don't like the idea too
much but
then again uh this is how human minds
work
so um yeah
yeah but we see we are
far away from the stage from that yeah
is there a way to easily start must be
more than carries
wheelhouse but start collecting people
who want
to volunteer they don't necessarily
write like everyone who joins projects
either has a project or wants to be part
of a project everyone joins game b
is basically has a project or is looking
for a project none of our projects are
at the space where someone can just come
in and be part of it at the same level
we are
um all of them could use labor right all
of them could use especially with the
data entry
and i feel like data entry is something
that's fairly accessible to most people
if you depending on what it is and how
complex it is that
most people if they knew about it would
want to give some time and so there's
there's what bentley had said where he's
going to pay people to do it
and both there's people who are like oh
yeah let's pay people
in venezuela to to do data entry
i'm willing to put 50 bucks towards that
knowing it's going to be maybe
you know like 10 hours worth of work or
whatever that there's funders
to pay for outsourcing especially if
it's for a bigger mission and then also
people who
um volunteer anyway just the volunteer
part like if people
when they come in or like it's like yes
here's an email list
if they're part of that email list they
know they're gonna get spam
from people who are like hey we need
volunteers for x right now
and once technology reaches the point
then of course it's not an email list
and it's a much
more fluid way to get those volunteers
and to find out
is it an in-person volunteer as a data
entry can i do it what five-minute
opportunities are there right now that i
could just do something right now
but like there's enough people
interested that it's not
future it is kind of now like it's
but i don't know whether doing any of
that work would get up to qrikets anyway
yeah i really want to help and then you
send out the email even if we had 50
people would anyone show up
i don't know we just moved this one to 2
p.m pornhuis it's like in the middle of
the night and
it's still just the five of us we'll do
one more week with this let's see well i
live in time zone
like spain
it's minus one hour ahead even further
not quite u.s but somewhere somewhere in
the pacific ocean
no no no well i think
it's actually late i i think if you'd
had sort of like a database of kind of
like
who wants to do what where the
when more like rather than just having a
list
of saying oh this is what we're doing
but like you need
sorry you would need to have um
[Music]
people who would actually want to do it
not just saying
that you want to be part of it you know
i mean
yeah and there's like the tech side of
like yes it'd be great to have i can put
all of my interest all of my specialties
everything in it would be like i want it
to go up to just the coders or just the
this but we're not at that level the
technologies that level i'm saying like
literally an email list it's like hey
you said you wanted to volunteer you
said you want to be part of like
game b or game b projects yes this is
happening on this on this day we need
people this is your call in and even if
we got one that'd be great the issue is
how much work goes into any kind of
output
right it definitely sounds like that
would end up being something that the
like that you know if the knack tool
were good it could have ended up doing
and the tool that
the the drupal site that carries working
on it sounds like it could pretty
easily turn into that i'm wondering if
there's
value in doing it off of software first
like we've sort of tried maybe different
versions of this in the game be projects
group but even saying like
in this meeting for you know the people
who here who have projects
that need work to decide on exactly what
work is needed
start to put that out like a weekly call
out to the group saying you know hey if
you're
looking to help with a project here's
five things that we need help with
yes if your project needs help feel free
to add a comment here and you know we'll
try to like
figure out how to keep that one updated
where it's i guess similar to like the
weekly status update but instead of
being a status update
it's uh who needs help and who's willing
to help
and you know knowing that the first like
using a comment thread in facebook
that's going to be super messy if it
actually
takes off but at that point that's a
good problem to have
so some other options would be email
lists
so pretty easy to set up as a google
group
and then we could post the link to sign
up for that anyone who wanted to could
sign up and then anyone
in that group could send an email to the
whole group so until it gets spammed
it would be good then there's other
things like sub stack
and i can't remember the name of the
other one where it's
it's free as long as you're not charging
for the email list and then
that'd be more like they could sign up
and then we could um
a specific person or group of dedicated
people could then send out emails to you
and maybe be worth setting up a
one-pager somewhere for game b
or on carrie's site or on the wiki that
says here are the email lists to get
notifications about
volunteering or new projects or
something like that
rather than having to to
hope that you see it in your facebook
feed or remember to go
look um so those are some options i
don't know what people think of that
it seems like there's two types of
volunteers one of which is like very
particular right i need someone who
knows codeine which
luckily we have a lot but like still
it's a very particular right i know to
go to mature bentley but like no
rest don't know but also the callouts
for like literally anyone can do this
right like that's a little bit me and my
solution is they like just come i don't
feel like i'm
you're an expert just come you have a
life that there
there's no requirement and therefore um
like if you can read and write numbers
you can probably do data entry
especially if it's um
repetitive and you're having multiple
people enter the same thing so it can
check off each other but um yeah an
email list for just
the the very low barrier volunteering
of like yes we want dozens of people
doing that entry
and growing that also becomes a source
of like we're not
emailing you unless it's good project
not just
anyone gets the email for for volunteer
um
and then that becomes a reason people
come and join anyway and
to be part of that if there's people on
that list that want to volunteer
yeah if we really want to curate it i'd
probably say
using sub stack or that other email one
although i don't know actually it may
only be one person can send them out so
that may be too much of a barrier
um i don't know if google group supports
you
um
to where only certain people can send
the emails or not
but yeah that would be something to look
into
do we do you really think that if we had
um
that we do have people that are willing
to no i mean i've seen a lot of people
i think there's like there's nobody to
put them
right like it's like people have asked
me like what can i do for your project
like i don't even know but if i had
a way to be like listen sign ups i'm
never doing a newsletter
and i'll give you the newsletter like
sign up and when there's a volunteer
opportunity
you will find out about it i might i
can't even do it that level but it feels
like together tech can do it at that
level where it's like hey even if there
isn't anything quite yet
we're i think we do have a mailchimp
account don't we from like months ago
and uh something but yeah
something along those lines well that's
right
i could i could set one up with what
yeah it's just it just sounded dead so
so basically
i could probably build something in that
you know would have somewhere
for people to go and say right okay we
need this this week
and just have it kind of like a notice
board and then we can post a link from
the notice boards
and then you know people with the
projects and and stuff like that can
you know um we can put it like it
towards the project and who's
who's offering what and then that would
be an easy way and then just post it
every week
and say right this week and sort of like
do a digest of like so i was looking for
this
i'm looking for that yeah can you i'll
give this and with that
because there's a lot of people who say
they're looking for the project to get
involved with
but they have um i don't know what what
they'd want to do because obviously you
don't want to be saying right
all these projects are needed help but
like because some people might think of
the help that's needed is a bit beneath
them you know i mean
so um i think i'd have to find out more
about
sort of like what people are needing and
that's why the the chat's really
important
um and i've chats with people with the
projects
and finding out properly and what
information they want out there
and whether they're wanting to have some
space where they can so they
just have other things in together as
well you know i mean so
as i said because we can start with with
us because we've got enough projects
to go with without that with now and
then so like build it out
so everybody you know and then you can
because people can start seeing once
tasks are done and once things are
starting to move
and i think that would be good for
people to see as well you know i mean so
i think
i think that's all possible
well i i just don't know if it'll be
effective unless they get
a direct notification somehow so a text
an email
what are some other a message through
facebook but that's kind of hard to do
yeah okay well as i said we can we can
look at that and build build
um i think with the crm module you can
do kind of like a campaign or do a
newsletter or we can do a newsletter
and for them to sign up with you know
what i mean and then that can take them
to the
straight to the page and that and
obviously we can sign them send links
for people to actually sign up if they
want to
and we'll just take it from there really
well i mean sending out emails and
getting them delivered consistently
will will be difficult without either
using sendgrid or
or mailchimp or substack
so you you can send it out from a base
server but until it's trusted it'll show
up in everyone's spams folder for the
most part
yeah in general i'm not a big fan of
email just because the deliverability
rates for email
have been going steadily downhill for
the last
okay well we can develop a social media
strategy then
[Applause]
i still think email's better
deliverability is fine as long as you're
using a known provider
right yeah if you use send grid so yeah
i don't just mean
like technical deliverability i mean
also like open rates well
open rates are untrackable because a lot
of the website
the google blocks
notifications so the open rates are not
accurate
um and you know that's more
based on the quality that people are
sending in and whether people open the
email
but i mean that i don't think there's a
better option it's bad
but i mean what else i mean if if
anything else it's like well let's just
post in the facebook group that's
everything else is
the same as the facebook group and we're
already doing that so let's
let's just be more intentional about it
but yeah
like i would like because we're close to
asking people to go off-site
for the the drupal tool personally i i'd
want to sort of
wait to use that request for the the
drupal site because if we're like hey go
check out mac
hey go sign up here for the email
newsletter hey go sign up for this hey
go sign up for that
that i think ended up creating a sort of
fatigue and it's not to say that you
know
that still won't happen with things like
the drupal site but
just to try to keep that to a minimum
and yeah knowing that the the facebook
option
isn't great either but it's just sort of
like we've already got them there
and it's no extra step to action it's
just do do they see it or not
and then the next time that we ask them
it's to sign up for this drupal tool
well yeah i just but are we asking them
i don't think kerry's suggestion was to
have them sign up for the drupal tool
what's the drupal goal
going to do with that sign up well as it
says it's just a case right
it's just to basically as i said once we
get the the project lists
and the ones some help that's needed and
we you know we've we've got that sorted
so everybody knows what's kind of what
they want and what you need and what
sort of help
and what you know um what's as i said if
we get that with the project
then people can actually we can post the
link to the project page
and then because all the contacts will
be there for that specific project
they can sign up to the to the person
directly rather than
having to sign up to the site because he
might not want to get involved in the
back end of it
um but as i said i just see the the back
end of the drupal
as a site to where we can actually put
all our stuff
and if there's plans and things you know
and you can have your own content and
you can see what's going on and other
people can see what's going on as well
so it's just a kind of sort of like a
as i said like a clubhouse you know so
you can right so
you know and see what's what and maybe
develop outwards and
as i said there'll be some people who
have a project you might want to come in
and play out with us and and that um
but not everybody's gonna want that so
as i said if i can get the project
page uh where they go to to find all the
projects we can
set up fields about help and what's
wanted and what's needed
so we and you can display the fields so
they can just see that and where to
contact the person directly if they they
want that you know what i mean and
which groups and give them more
information um
if they need it so basically we just put
a link to the
the project page um
of all the projects so they can go and
have a mooch through
and as i said you can display it whether
helps want it
helps need it you know what i mean and
what status the projects are
and if you know and if somebody's just
got ideas
that they want to come along and talk to
somebody about they don't know
you know as i said it's just a seat of
an idea but they want to help grow it
then
if they want they can come and join the
back end of it because i think
there's kind of nowhere because it's out
in the public you don't really want
um people if you've just got a seed of
an idea you don't know where you're
going with it
you don't really want everybody looking
at it and going oh you're an idiot
you know that'll never take off but you
want to be able to talk to somebody
and talk some talk talk through it with
somebody
and then maybe we can do that in the
back end of it and then
either because as i said we you know
you'll have to join to see that
but it'll be you know be a a safer place
to kind of like an idea factory
something like that where you can just
bounce about and don't no matter how
out there it is you know i mean you're
not gonna get laughed out of town
or run out of town for having an idea
that looks a bit mad
you know what i mean right i think
like what the the question that i sort
of heard
brantley ask and what led to this
conversation from my understanding
is you know how do we get our facebook
audience to sort of
what's the step to start to drive this
sort of action and i
think if we're saying that the next step
is the drupal tool
i don't think the first version will
have everybody signing up for a member
i'm not expecting this question i think
it probably starts out being just carrie
and then the the the next step are the
project owners
and then it just becomes sort of a
portal where i for four week election
can go say here what's going on with
wikilection
oh and by the way here's what we need
help with and then there's some page on
the site that just you know
if bentley lists something in isla
something emma touch and jubilee and
carrie and
everybody who has a project each list
two or three things that we need help
with
there's just a page showing here's
everything and
in the first version they're probably
like it just says if you want to
participate go reach out to that
project then yeah and then eventually we
might get to the point where those
people actually sign up for a member
account and there's the whole like idea
ecosystem but i think to answer b b
question in the start they wouldn't sign
up it would just be like
go there and read it and then we still
have the the issue of
will they go read it or do we also then
you know put in an email and also post
it on facebook
like how do we start uh i think it's
like you know like
it's um content media
planning strategies which involve social
media strategies as well so
once once you've got it up and running
as i said at the back end of it we can
actually develop
some content and and some social media
strategies
in order to do that so so that would
take care of that bit
you know so and then so that would be
fine but as i said i'm not expecting
anyone to sign up
um and you know as i said if people who
want to they can
to be more than welcome but as i said
it's not going to be everybody's cup of
tea which
i'm fine with but there's going to be
the projects in the open so they can
actually see
and other stuff will be in the open what
you know what we want them to see
well everyone to see will be in the open
so they can read it without
you know having to join or anything as i
said
i don't you know as you know and then if
they get inspired and if
they're interested there's there's
plenty of space for them
if they want to you know what i mean so
um yeah
and i think that's the advantage over
the neck tool was when i built the
actual it was built around
project owners signing up and sort of
managing their pages and people were
doing that so there's no information
and i think the drupal tool that you're
creating the advantage is that if you're
willing to do the work to sort of like
manage the projects and get it you know
get and keep enough content in there to
to keep it interesting
to the point where some people are
starting to use it as you know project
participants and other people are trying
to use it as project owners
i think that's really where the inactual
flat was it just didn't get actual users
which is a pretty important part of the
project
well i said guess what i see myself as a
little like a community student right
i'm not not in charge
it's not just all about me and basically
so
so say like for the project listing
being the public right the
research into collaboration tools put
that out there findings and stuff like
that
and things that people will find useful
like as i said make that all in the open
and i may have a thing like buy us a
coffee or something
um on the list whatever but if they find
it useful but as i said but having
information like the the collaboration
tools and maybe if we go in depth and
as i said content and media and social
strategies and
community building strategies we can
make all that information open
so anyone with the project is maybe
thinking about it and as i said if you
want to come and join it
join us for some solidarity and some you
know i mean as i said
the more the more we are together as
and as long as we see it that we're not
trying to take their project off them
like they're
free to you know have you know projects
but also if you can
think of something that we haven't
thought of you know what i mean so it's
just kind of help each other out
kind of big tent like a circus tent
[Laughter]
really
yeah i i would i didn't have any problem
with that i
i guess just the thing was that that
didn't seem to like
answer what jubilee asked so
i was just wanting to make sure we
and i'm also much more okay waiting for
the drupal tool than whatever we were
doing that it was like
years ago like eventually we'll get to
create this
i don't have the need for volunteers at
the moment so
it's more for the sense making projects
like when you guys do need your army of
of data entry and it might be ready by
then and then we can together figure out
a social media strategy
to um like once we have some people can
sign up
we can all tweet and facebook like hey
want to come save the world like
actually put hours to your
vision come be part of this if you care
about politics i'll be part of this if
you care about science you know
i think in the short term anytime we
want to do a volunteers needed
i just i wouldn't want
there's been some people that like post
their weekly meetings i don't
want that to be like a weekly post from
everybody where they all ask hey
come join my meeting um
but so maybe a weekly post that if you
need volunteers
um separate from the i mean that we
asked for help in the
weekly update um but someone who's
volunteering
i mean roy they should check that but i
don't know
that they do maybe it doesn't matter i
don't know what you all think
i think we're probably good with what
we're doing right now i was going to say
it's like it feels frustrating because
we've been doing it like week after week
that's just the five of us but i'm also
like right
a year ago there weren't the five of us
i mean i knew adriel we go way back but
like besides that
right like i felt very alone in this for
years and it's like hey if there's five
of us
and we're like dedicated yes we're not
working on one project besides the other
side of course
but like there's something very powerful
happening that i'm very
i'm i have less stress about all of
these tools not being in existence
because the people are coming together
and
although we need both the people are
more important tools without people or
fucking shit workers people without
tools we can still do it we can figure
it out
yep yeah i think so
so we have what 12 minutes left 13
minutes left
is that enough time to get into your
thing bentley
i don't know we could start see how it
goes uh
of course i don't know where to start
with it
um
so one of my main questions when i was
trying to figure out sort of how or if
wiki election can tie in is
what sort of evidence are we considering
and what does that look like
well from the system standpoint it
wouldn't
matter so anything anyone considers
evidence
so right so i guess like what are some
lists that we can use to populate that
because
i like for example i had the idea for
wikilection for a long time like oh it's
going to be evidence-based and then i
actually went to go look for evidence
and i'm like oh it's not all that
like it's available but it's weird and
piecemeal and then there's the other
side of
what do people actually trust
well no but but see you're not i so i
would flip it
around and say that you're not looking
for evidence of people trust
you're allowing people to say this is
why i believe
this and then they put in their evidence
and then other people can come in and
put in their evidence
so there's not a category for evidence
evidence is anything anyone thinks is
evidence and you just link out to it
um and then people can then discuss and
debate that evidence
so there's there's no pre-population
needed or categorization in my mind
because
i don't care whether it's a video or a
text it's just a it's just a hyperlink
right so if we're talking specifically
about
voting with your wallet right so let's
say like
what's an example of so like
it and this question is i guess for
anyone more like as a consumer for
somebody that wants to use the site
if you were trying to shop for i don't
know bread
and it was saying like hey here's three
companies and saying this company is
great and that company sucks
if you were like brand new to the site
and you wanted to dig a bit deeper
what would the evidence look like or
what sort of evidence would you either
be like oh i don't trust it or like oh
that's perfect
um for something like you know that
company is great for
paying their staff for example like
i'm not sure what the evidence would
look like would that just be a bunch of
staff
that are willing to go on record saying
that they paid me 10
an hour or would it actually be like
something available in that country
let's kind of step through the
the user uh journey
so you come to the site let's say you're
you're trying to figure out where you're
gonna buy your daily coffee right so
that's something you buy consistently
right
so you might just go to the site type in
coffee and then you would say well
here's our top several now of course
the coffee may not be in your area so
then you may want to narrow it down to
say where you live
and then it would filter down to that
and then it would say well
here's our general ratings of the
companies like
you know just talk five four three two
one and then here's kind of why
and it would say well this one uh there
was a news
this one this lower one's lower because
there was a news article
saying that their employees weren't
there or we could even take the um
the starbucks issue so like let's say
are they uh sensitive to the racial
issues in the united states
and there was that news article where a
guy was the police were called on him
and
and he was um i can't remember
specifically what went on
so someone might say oh you know they're
not good with
um social activism
because of that and then someone might
come back and say oh well they shut down
for two days
a week later and retrained all their
staff on cultural sensitivity and stuff
like that
so those two pieces of evidence would be
put in
um so you know if there is no evidence
whether they're good or bad
i don't think there's anything we can do
about that um
but where there is evidence now if if
you're if you're going and you look at
those coffee things and you can see some
of the categories are like we rate
this company high on on social but but
low
on um on environmentalism
right then you can then say oh well i
social is more important to me than
environmentalism so i can like hit a
button that says this is more important
to me
and then the the list would then resort
to show who's on top
so that's the way i kind of envision
okay so it
sounds like for the end user one of the
lower
or one of the lowest levels of sort of
like pieces of evidence
are the various news articles talking
about something right so yeah like for
starbucks there's
here's 10 news articles talking about
that situation where like i got i
was like a barista called the cops on a
black guy who was just waiting in a
starbucks
for just for just being black and
waiting i guess right um
and then yes starbucks had a bunch of
stories written about that that there
was the blowback and then there was a
bunch of stories written about how
hey starbucks shut down for a couple of
days and the various kinds of
sensitivity training
um and so that and
i actually think that's one of the
better sources that we have right now
are those kind of news articles and then
sort of
grouping them together to say hey here's
something that a hundred different
outlets
wrote about here's the 100 you know
here's 100 articles that were written
and here's that one thing that they
wrote about and there's the other thing
whereas okay that's
the incident and then there's the you
know what they did about it
and so there's these two separate things
backed up by a bunch of
news articles right right but also
someone could go in and look at their
um quarterly earnings statements and say
you know with the amount of money
they're earning
and maybe somewhere in the statements
they say what their average pay is for a
barista
they might say that's inappropriate and
so that could be evidence right so
that's not a news article but it's a
link it's
it's an internet link um you know and
maybe
maybe you post some videos of
the um of the ceo on cnn
saying something about you know lying
about their company and stuff like that
or
you know the the you know what snippets
from
the you know mark zuckerberg in front of
congress
right right um so all those things would
be kind of like evidence and you could
say what
feature that's affecting and and then
people can kind of debate
whether it should or should not affect
it and how much it should affect it
right that's my thought now i i think a
lot of people may not be willing to put
in that
that level of information so there will
be i imagine
there would need to be i would rather
not have it but i think we'll need to
have just a popularity option so you can
go and say oh i don't really like
starbucks and then
they say oh well tell us why you like it
is it because they're socially
responsible is it because they
you know so then you could rate each
individual thing and then when you rate
them maybe say oh do you have any
evidence other than what we already have
and you could show if someone's already
posted news articles here what they have
are we missing anything especially if
their ratings differ from a majority of
other people then you can say
why what's the reason why you have that
so you just kind of slowly
uh bring them deeper into it if they're
willing to and then we can talk about
how the system could be abused and
figure that out but
right that's the general idea yeah and i
i think that last part it like
no matter what it has to go through a
phase where it gets abused and we just
you know kind of try to keep it mostly
silent while we're trying to figure that
part out and like
don't publicize the outcome too much but
we're like hey we started to collect
this here's the prototype
but yeah it's fully able to be gamed
right now and we're aware of that
like so do you see that flow also
working for wiki election like
and even whether you have your
professionals but a public thing that
comes in let them
just say what they like about their
candidates
and then another evidence on why they
think the candidates are that way or
does that not work
to an extent that's how it works my goal
is to sort of take
the end of like the individual opinion i
really only want
at the level of like i have an opinion
on what this piece of evidence means and
sort of you know
the outcome that people are saying that
this evidence means x is that true or
not and then you know
what's your your uh either like your
track record
if you've said you know that these 20
past instances i like that and didn't
like that do you 10 agree with the
experts or not i mean you know
are you qualified in other ways um
but very little about like trying to get
an aggregate of like
somebody posting a comment and like it's
i guess starting from the evidence then
trying to figure out how to uh
how to review it and then how to group
it into various things
and for that i use the events like i
talked about where for starbucks you've
got okay here's the event
of the cops being called here's the
event of
you know the the training afterwards and
then the community would then sort of
score
those events and then you can also do
scoring on the events for
people said that this wasn't good but it
also only had one news article written
about it so we're not 100 sure
what's actually happening um and then
you get deep into that okay well what
news outlets published that if there's
five articles but they're all written
by maybe less than reputable outlets
how do you judge that but it in
wikileaks it really all starts from the
evidence
and then you start to group it and score
it and review it and so on and yeah
that's
so yeah so the feature i didn't have in
my list yet that you mentioned
was or the big one was um experts
yeah um
and then there were some other nuances
in there so we'd have to see whether
those nuances like i think the experts
would
would happen in all these things because
if you have someone who's
knows nutritional science then if
they're including that um
that chemical in their food in the
ingredients list then that could be
something that's important
and of course for the food piece the
ingredients list is something that
doesn't quite fit with everything else i
mean maybe that's just
called an evidence and maybe that maybe
we can just shoehorn that into the same
structure
and then give it a different name on
that site yeah i mean this is
quite thought through all those kind of
where hyperlogos would be useful
where it's like you might have a section
that has the evidence about
the um the individual ingredients is
sort of like okay so
if you're saying that aspartame is
healthy or not great then what are all
the studies underlying that so anytime
aspartame comes up
you've got this underlying bed of
information about that one ingredient
that if you're referencing it in like
okay i'm not as concerned about the
company i just want to make sure i'm
eating something that's healthy
okay great here's you know from what
you've said and the kinds of sources
that you trust and don't trust
here's how the evidence currently boils
down and based on the evidence for
aspartame you know the community has
shown that it's either safe or not safe
or you know it's safe to eat but don't
inject it or however that information is
actually
split out so the question comes down to
is all these little nuances
for each community in each project
going to be so different from the other
ones
that how much code is actually going to
be able to be shared right
right so that would be part of the
architecture and maybe in the first
couple of things maybe
experts won't be in it or maybe the
ingredients
won't be in it on the food one although
that's pretty core to it
but so i think we kind of have to map
out the
feature requirements and then seeing
even though the names will differ
the the core data structures if they're
similar enough it may not right
matter whether it's an ingredient or or
a feature for a website
but but maybe it does so yeah
i'm wondering what uh i guess this is
mostly a question for
for bentley amatouche but like take
something like the vote with your wallet
thing
build sort of like the really you know
popsicle sticks and glue
prototype that like were you know that
i'm e effectively
working with matush to build full wiki
election knowing that that's not going
to be long term
i'm making a bunch of design choices
that aren't great for the long term and
that won't handle certain situations
but just to get a vibe for it and see
like what works any
glaring issues and in the case of wiki
election it's focusing on
uh on politics and that in the case of
confronting it's focusing on sort of
organizations and the same type of
history that what will be available
i wonder if the end goal is to start
with that level of prototype for
something like vote with your wallet
don't worry about trying to tie them
together at all and then meet up you
know in three months and see what we
have in common
i start to like after once they're
starting to to do stuff and then we say
oh they overlapped
great here not so great there and then
we can talk about the pros and cons of
each
and could we overlap or should they keep
on their you know
pads we're running out of time but my
almost
feeling is because when things kind of
when they're designed
kind of separately like that you tend to
make naming conventions
and concepts that are different enough
that'd be really hard to recombine them
in the end
but if you say everyone's going to want
to have an entity that they vote on
and attributes of those entities that
they vote on all of them do have that
piece
the evidence and the and that sort of
thing i don't know we got to look at
that
that maybe just building up that piece
and using it in all three
um i that that would be my preferred
path
right i i see so like
have sort of a pre-planning prior to the
prototype so that we're at least
more set up to follow the same general
structure
and then knowing that we'll still add
things onto our prototypes that might be
unique
but at least you know like you're you're
starting from people and organizations
and positions and
the general structure of like so we're
talking the same language for if we're
trying to look at what
person worked where and who donated what
that there's hopefully some
yeah i think there's i think there is a
core
of shared functionality that's obviously
shared and then there's the more stuff
that we might want to figure
out how to work together um so i'd like
to work on that core a little bit right
first
okay hopefully i wonder and i know you
guys were
at the end but like the if an event
happens and it's newsworthy
and then everyone covers it that gets a
high score but if something's newsworthy
and no one covers it because that's what
happens in the media right there's a
protest that like crickets nobody looked
at it
what no news source picked it up but
there's hundreds of people with cell
phones right it's it's the difference
um and that is partly like my my focus
of starting with
the ground base of the people but we
don't have 10 000 people so that would
be ridiculous for you guys to stop your
projects
for thousands of people that like how
how the average person gets their
information on food and how you're going
to trust it and how you get your
information on politicians because
politic
they're very different like like science
i don't want news articles i want it
back to the scientific article
politicians there's no scientific
article it is was it covered in the news
and was it spoken
at you know like actually recorded and
spoken in the votes and stuff
so it's like back to the evidence like
none of the evidence would i trust would
be like well this was covered 500 times
in the news because i
already the news that's what we're
fixing like it's already
that like the amount of times it's
covered in the news is not the same as
the amount of times that a
peer-reviewed article has sourced
another one revised and even that's
broken
but like the bigger picture of that is
like well
yeah i can link to that story first of
all that starbucks guy
starbucks didn't say go kick him out an
employee said i'm going to pick him up
starbucks response didn't fire that
employee they're like we're gonna have
training for everyone
like it's like well did they do did
starbucks do wrong
i don't know starbucks do right yeah
yeah like it's like you know like
but as a society we focus on no
starbucks kicked the guy out in
starbucks
right but the in the system is the
ability to rate
the evidence and debate it so nowhere
would we say oh the frequency of newer
articles have any
bearing on it or we would say oh we
trust studies more than others that will
come out of the wash because the system
says you could link anything
so like you said no news coverage well
there's youtube videos so you link a
youtube video
yeah um so yeah so it's unrelated to
the media the media just happens to be
one of the sources
and i think for something like the
protests you're going to end up with a
huge amount of both
and a lot of them won't agree with each
other and then that's where the review
of the
on you know if you had an article about
the black lives matter protest in the us
you would end up with a thousand news
articles and 500 000 youtube videos
yeah and then it's like okay so now you
kind of go through and find
the common findings and you have some
people go through and start to flag out
to like
okay i'm just going to pull up with no
context just the instances of police
brutality
then you're gonna have somebody else
going and pull up just the the writers
doing bad things
and then if everyone's doing it with the
same source you can start to be like
okay
here's what the different sides are
doing and then you can pull it back and
say like okay
now let's add some context to those
videos and let's start to see
what numbers are we talking about
because if there's you know 10 of this
and
you know 10 instances of police
brutality and 10 rioters
and a million protesters like oh maybe
the extremes aren't
actually driving this conversation
despite what people are saying
or if one you know is ten percent one is
one percent you're like oh
one side is obviously clear you know
clearly worse here
but if like even in the riots and i
agree that those numbers probably
showcase very
heavily one way that actually no it
helps both sides
that like you don't know the cops or the
cops when they're quitting police
brutality you don't know protesters or
protesters when they're committing the
violence right so
how do i know that was a cop and not
just somebody who wanted you to think
cops are
having police brutality that's less
likely to happen because there's a much
higher legal precedent
than the cops getting in black all black
right and being like we'll just smash
the windows and start some fires that
everyone else does
that it one it happened and there was
one incident and a human being
started this fire now how do we know
whether they're you know this or that
and that's part of
for me any sense making tool is owning
that well we don't know how to own that
right like we know what's going on in
the protest we know they're happening
maybe maybe because the media's not
covering them as much as they could
if there's something there but we're
like three minutes pass should we end
this or should we continue
recording i think yeah
all right thanks misery thanks people
for showing up for the two
2 p.m one the same